URL,Link
http://www.freddiemac.com,"Freddie Mac Home
(opens in new window)"
https://sf.freddiemac.com/,"Single-Family Division
Insights, products, and technology to help you grow your business.
(opens in new window)"
https://my.sf.freddiemac.com/,"Client Resource Center
Resources, training, System Status, and FAQ to help you run your business.
(opens in new window)"
/app/guide/home,"Seller/Servicer Guide
Learn how to work with us with our Guide Bulletins and Industry Letters."
https://mf.freddiemac.com/,"Multifamily Division
(opens in new window)"
http://capitalmarkets.freddiemac.com/capital-markets/,"Capital Markets Division
/app/guide,"Renters, Buyers and Owners"
https://myhome.freddiemac.com/,"My Home by Freddie Mac®
Resources to help you rent, buy and own your home.
(opens in new window)"
https://loanlookup.freddiemac.com/,"Do we own your mortgage?
Find out if Freddie Mac owns your loan using our secure lookup tool.
(opens in new window)"
https://myhome.freddiemac.com/renting/lookup,"Did we finance your apartment?
Use our lookup tool to see if Freddie Mac financed your apartment building.
(opens in new window)"
https://creditsmart.freddiemac.com/,"CreditSmart®
Financial and homeownership education resources all about you.
(opens in new window)"
/app/guide/home,Seller/ServicerGuide
/app/guide/home,Guide Home
/app/guide/segment/Seller%2FServicer%20Relationship,Seller/Servicer Relationship
/app/guide/segment/Selling,Selling
/app/guide/segment/Servicing,Servicing
/app/guide/segment/Seller%2FServicer%20Relationship,Browse Seller/Servicer Relationship
0: The Guide
0: General Freddie Mac Policies
0: General Responsibilities of the Seller/Servicer
0: Electronic Transactions
/app/guide/topic/1500,"1500: Seller Master Agreements, other Pricing Identifier Terms and Guide Plus Additional Provisions"
0: Seller/Servicer Institutional Eligibility
0: Additional Requirements for Doing Business with Freddie Mac
0: Disqualification or Suspension of a Seller/Servicer
0: Access to Freddie Mac Tools and Systems
0: Freddie Mac Exclusionary List and FHFA Suspended Counterparty Program
/app/guide/topic/3200,"3200: Fraud Prevention, Detection and Reporting; Reporting Other Suspicious Activity"
0: Mortgage File Contents and Retention
0: Quality Control
0: Freddie Mac Servicer Success Performance and File Reviews
0: Remedies (Including Repurchase and Termination of Servicing)
/app/guide/segment/Selling,Browse Selling
0: Uniform Instruments
0: General Mortgage Eligibility
0: Loan Purpose
0: Special Mortgage Eligibility Requirements
0: Affordable Mortgages and Duty to Serve
0: Special Freddie Mac Mortgage Products
0: Insurance Requirements
0: Determining Borrower Eligibility
0: Credit Assessment
0: Stable Monthly Income and Asset Qualification Sources
0: Evaluation of Monthly Obligations
0: Assets
0: Property Eligibility and Appraisal Requirements
0: Property
0: Uniform Closing Dataset
0: Automated Income and Asset Assessment with Loan Product Advisor
0: Cash Program
0: Guarantor and MultiLender Swap Programs
0: Delivery of All Mortgages
0: Nondelivery
/app/guide/segment/Servicing,Browse Servicing
0: Transfers of Servicing
0: General Freddie Mac Servicing Policies
0: Escrow and Insurance
0: Servicing Performing Loans – Investor Accounting and Remitting
0: Property Matters
0: Servicing for Special Mortgages
0: Servicing Requirements for Senior Subordinate Mortgages
0: Servicing Requirements for Community Land Trust Mortgages
0: Servicing Requirements for Cooperative Share Loans
0: Servicing Requirements for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
0: Delinquencies
0: Loss Mitigation
0: Foreclosure
0: Bankruptcy and Other Litigation Involving Freddie Mac-Owned or Guaranteed Mortgages
/app/guide/topic/9500,"9500: Selection, Retention and Management of Law Firms for Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters"
0: Post-Foreclosure/Real Estate Owned
0: Reimbursement of Expenses
/app/guide/bulletins,Bulletins & Industry Letters
/app/guide/revisions,Upcoming Changes
/app/guide/forms,Forms
/app/guide/exhibits,Exhibits
/app/guide/glossary,Glossary
/app/guide/directories,Directory
/app/guide/archive,Archives
https://www.allregs.com/tpl/public/fhlmc_freesite_tll.aspx,AllRegs(opens in new window)
https://sf.freddiemac.com/tools-learning/uniform-instruments/2021-updated-instruments,Uniform Instruments(opens in new window)
https://sf.freddiemac.com/working-with-us/selling-delivery/delivery-options-pricing/document-custody,Document Custody Procedures Handbook(opens in new window)
/app/guide/glossary,Glossary
https://www.allregs.com/tpl/public/fhlmc_freesite_tll.aspx,AllRegs(opens in new window)
https://sf.freddiemac.com/tools-learning/uniform-instruments/2021-updated-instruments,Uniform Instruments(opens in new window)
/app/guide/home,Featured Resources
/app/guide/browse,Browse Guide
/app/guide/bulletins,Recent Bulletins
/app/guide/forms,Forms & Documents
/app/guide/revisions,Upcoming Changes
/app/guide/archive,Archives
,1101.1:Introduction to the Guide
,1101.2:Legal effect of the Guide and other Purchase Documents
,1101.3:Occurrence of a Claims Event; resulting liability immediately due and owing to Freddie Mac
,1201.1:Objective of Freddie Mac's purchase programs
,1201.2:Overview of Freddie Mac's purchase programs
,1201.3:Characterization and nature of Mortgage purchase transactions
,1201.4:Limitation on Mortgage purchases and commitments
,1201.5:Servicing in accordance with Purchase Documents
,1201.6:Transfer costs
,1201.7:Sale of Mortgages by Freddie Mac
,1201.8:Receipt and treatment of confidential information
,"1201.9:The Mortgage file, Mortgage data and related records"
,"1201.10:Minority-Owned, Women-Owned and Disabled-Owned Business Enterprises"
,1201.11:Audit confirmation requests
,1301.1:Submission of data to Freddie Mac
,1301.2:Compliance with applicable law
,1301.3:Inspection of records
,1301.4:Reliance on the Seller/Servicer warranties and representations
,1301.5:Review of Mortgages by Freddie Mac prior to purchase
,1301.6:Seller authorized to sell Mortgage
,1301.7:Servicer authorized to service
,1301.8:Warranties and representations by the Seller
,1301.9:Servicer agreements
,1301.10:Survival of warranties; remedies
,"1301.11:Enforcement of representations and warranties related to underwriting of the Borrower, Mortgaged Premises and project"
,1301.12:Non-discrimination
,1302.1:Overview of information security and business continuity planning requirements
,1302.2:Information security
,1302.3:Business continuity planning
,1401.1:Electronic Transactions
,1401.2:Defined terms
,1401.3:Requirements applicable to all Eligible Electronic Transactions
,1401.4:Consent and agreement to engage in and conduct Eligible Electronic Transactions
,1401.5:Security standards for all Eligible Electronic Transactions engaged in or conducted by the Seller/Servicer
,1401.6:Security standards for Eligible Electronic Transactions engaged in or conducted by the Seller/Servicer's TPPs
,1401.7:Seller's due diligence requirements for the Seller's Systems used to engage in or conduct Eligible Electronic Transactions
,1401.8:Seller's due diligence requirements for TPP's Systems used for Eligible Electronic Transactions
,1401.9:Electronic Signatures
,1401.10:Additional requirements for Initial Loan Documents and Closing Documents
,1401.11:Eligible Electronic Initial Loan Documents and Electronic Closing Documents – Retail Mortgages
,1401.12:Eligible Electronic Initial Loan Documents and Electronic Closing Documents – Wholesale Home Mortgages
,1401.13:Electronic real estate purchase and sale agreements
,1401.14:Electronic Recording of paper Closing Documents and post-closing documents
,1401.15:Electronic Recording of Electronic Closing Documents
,1401.16:Electronically Notarized (In-Person or Remote Online) Electronic Documents
,1401.17:Electronic Transactions conducted between Servicer and Borrower
,"1401.18:Representations, warranties and covenants for Eligible Electronic Transactions engaged in or conducted by the Seller/Servicer with Freddie Mac"
,"1401.19:Representations, warranties and covenants for Eligible Electronic Transactions engaged in or conducted by the Seller/Servicer's TPPs"
,1401.20:Indemnification
,1401.21:Electronic Transaction liability
,1401.22:Law governing Electronic Transactions
,1401.23:Delivery requirements for Mortgages closed using Remote Online Electronic Notarization
,1401.24:Remote Ink Notarization
,1402.1:Introduction to eMortgages
,1402.2:Defined terms
,1402.3:Selling eMortgages
,1402.4:eClosing requirements
,1402.5:eNote Vault System requirements
,1402.6:eNote Vault System/eClosing Systems encryption requirements
,1402.7:Eligible eMortgage types and products
,1402.8:Closing and delivering eMortgages
,1402.9:Servicing eMortgages
,1402.10:Servicing performing eMortgages
,1402.11:Servicing non-performing eMortgages
,1402.12:Mortgage File Documents management requirements
,1402.13:Transfer of Servicing involving eMortgages
,1402.14:Special eMortgage Servicing representations and warranties
,1402.15:Voluntary eMortgage repurchase request
,1402.16:Warehouse Lender requirements
,1402.17:New York CEMA Refinance of New York eMortgage
,1402.18:eNote custodian requirements
,1501.1:Master Agreements and other Pricing Identifier Terms
,1501.2:Terms of Master Agreements and other Pricing Identifier Terms
,1501.3:Guide Plus Additional Provisions
,"1501.4:Contracts, delivery programs and procedures"
,1501.5:Credit toward a Commitment Amount or any dollar amount stated in a Master Agreement
,"1501.6:Contract tolerances, pairoffs"
,1501.7:Remittance cycles
,1501.8:Revocation of Master Agreement and/or other Pricing Identifier Terms
,2101.1:Eligibility criteria
,2101.2:Acceptable Net Worth and other financial requirements
,2101.3:Activity thresholds and no-activity fee
,2101.4:Financial reporting
,2101.5:Mortgage bankers financial reporting
,2101.6:Seller/Servicer insurance requirements
,2101.7:Fidelity insurance coverage
,2101.8:Mortgagee's errors and omissions (E&O) insurance coverage
,2101.9:Seller/Servicer insurance reporting requirements
,2101.10:Annual certification
,2101.11:Annual reporting requirements
,2101.12:Reporting of changes in Seller/Servicer's organization or status
,2101.13:Transfer of assets to an entity that is not a Freddie Mac-approved Seller/Servicer
,2101.14:Seller/Servicer changes that result in a Transfer of Servicing
,2201.1:Seller/Servicer Certificate of Incumbency requirements
,2201.2:Establishing and maintaining wire transfer instructions for cash proceeds
,2202.1:Document Custodian
,2202.2:Document Custodian eligibility
,2202.3:Contracting with a Document Custodian
,2202.4:Document Custodian duties to Freddie Mac
,2202.5:Seller/Servicer and the Document Custodian
,2202.6:Transfer of custody and terminating Tri-Party Agreements
,2203.1:MERS® membership
,2301.1:Disqualification or suspension of Seller's eligibility to sell
,2301.2:Disqualification or suspension of the Seller or the Servicer
,2301.3:Notice of intent to disqualify or suspend the Seller or the Servicer
,2301.4:Request for voluntary termination of status as a Freddie Mac Seller or Servicer
,2301.5:Appeal
,2301.6:Final decision
,2401.1:Master Systems License
,2402.1:System-Specific License for Specifications
,2402.2:System-Specific License for Freddie Mac Loan Advisor®
,2402.3:System-Specific License for Loan Product Advisor®
,2402.4:System-Specific License for Loan Quality Advisor®
,2402.5:System-Specific License for Loan Coverage Advisor®
,2402.6:System-Specific License for Loan Selling Advisor®
,2402.7:System-Specific License for HVE®
,2402.8:System-Specific License for Quality Control Advisor®
,2402.9:System-Specific License for Freddie Mac Servicing Data Corrections
,2403.1:Sale of Mortgages through Loan Selling Advisor®
,2403.2:Termination of eligibility
,2403.3:Use of Selling Agents
,2403.4:Termination of eligibility
,2403.5:Incorporation of Loan Selling Advisor® into the Purchase Documents
,2403.6:Special representations and warranties
,2403.7:Consent to conduct Electronic Transactions
,2403.8:System security
,2403.9:Access to copies of transaction records
,2403.10:System requirements
,2403.11:User roles
,2403.12:Post-Fund Data Correction tool
,2404.1:System-Specific License for Specifications
,2404.2:Servicing Gateway System-Specific License
,2404.3:Freddie Mac Servicing Reporting Tools incorporated into the Guide
,2404.4:Amendments
,"2404.5:Special representations and warranties, covenants and agreements"
,2404.6:Electronic Transactions
,2404.7:Security and Servicer responsibilities
,2404.8:Access to copies of Electronic Transaction Records
,2405.1:Process for requesting expense reimbursement and for receiving reimbursement of expenses
,2405.2:Servicer bound by use of PAID (Payments Automated Intelligent and Dynamic)
,2405.3:Consent to conduct Electronic Transactions
,2405.4:System security
,2405.5:Access to copies of Electronic Transaction Records
,2405.6:User access requirements
,2405.7:Use of PAID (Payments Automated Intelligent and Dynamic) by Related Third Parties and process for Related Third Parties to receive reimbursement of expenses
,2405.8:Servicer's responsibilities for the Reimbursement System
,2406.1:Workout Prospector® User Agreement
,2406.2:Quality Control Advisor®
,2406.3:Freddie Mac Loan Coverage Advisor®
,2406.4:Managing access to and obtaining a property value via BPODirect®
,2406.5:Freddie Mac Default Fee Appeal System
,2407.1:Attorney Data Reporting
,"2408.1:Relation to Chapters 2404, 2405, 2406 and 2407"
,2408.2:Using Servicing Tools and Excluded Servicing Tools
,2408.3:Freddie Mac Servicing Tools incorporated into the Guide
,2408.4:Amendments
,"2408.5:Special representations and warranties, covenants and agreements"
,2408.6:Electronic Transactions
,2408.7:Access to copies of Electronic Transaction Records
,3101.1:Freddie Mac Exclusionary List
,3101.2:FHFA Suspended Counterparty Program
,3201.1:Prevention and detection
,3201.2:Fraud and other Suspicious Activity reporting requirements
,3201.3:Cooperation requirements
,3201.4:Additional requirements
,3201.5:Additional fraud mitigation resources
,3301.1:Mortgage file
,3301.2:Security Instrument
,"3301.3:New York Consolidation, Extension and Modification Agreement"
,3301.4:Assignment instrument
,3301.5:Power of attorney
,3301.6:Plat of survey
,3301.7:Property insurance policies
,3301.8:Assurance of water supply
,3301.9:Mortgage insurance policy
,3301.10:Leasehold estate
,3301.11:Additional documentation to be retained in Mortgage file
,3302.1:Maintaining Mortgage file
,3302.2:Form of Mortgage file documents
,3302.3:Mortgage file control and identification
,3302.4:Damage or loss of Mortgage file
,3302.5:Transfer of Mortgage files; security of Mortgage file information
,3401.1:Postfunding quality control
,3401.2:Credit enhancer postfunding review
,3401.3:Note
,3401.4:Modifying instrument or assumption of indebtedness agreement
,3401.5:Underwriting summary
,3401.6:Title insurance
,3401.7:Residential loan application
,3401.8:Credit documentation
,3401.9:Verification of employment and income
,3401.10:Underwriting explanation
,3401.11:Property valuation documentation
,3401.12:Appraisal form rental information
,3401.13:Leasehold Mortgage
,3401.14:Buydown agreement
,3401.15:Mortgage insurance certificate
,3401.16:Mortgage payment history
,3401.17:Verification of source of funds
,3401.18:Verification of previous Mortgage/rental payment history
,3401.19:Sales contract
,3401.20:Closing statements
,3401.21:Documentation of flood zone determination
,3401.22:Evidence of flood insurance
,3401.23:Other documentation
,3401.24:Mortgage secured by a Manufactured Home
,3401.25:Settlement/Closing Disclosure Statement
,3401.26:Secondary financing
,3401.27:Freddie Mac Relief Refinance Mortgage℠ – Same Servicer
,3401.28:Electronic Records and Electronic Signatures
,3401.29:Community Land Trust Mortgage
,3401.30:GreenCHOICE Mortgages®
,3402.1:Seller's quality control program
,3402.2:Use of third-party quality control services
,3402.3:Transfers of Servicing
,3402.4:Postclosing sample selection
,3402.5:Reverifications made by Seller
,3402.6:Data integrity review
,3402.7:Documentation review
,3402.8:Preclosing quality control reviews
,3402.9:Documenting reviews
,3402.10:Reporting requirements
,3402.11:Retention of Seller's quality control records
,3403.1:Servicer's quality control program
,3501.1:Freddie Mac Servicer Success File Reviews
,3501.2:Servicer performance metrics
,3601.1:Freddie Mac remedies
,3602.1:Defined terms
,3602.2:Repurchases required by Freddie Mac due to violations of sale representations and warranties
,3602.3:Repurchases and repurchase alternatives required by Freddie Mac due to Servicing violations
,3602.4:Repurchases requested by the Seller/Servicer
,3602.5:Repurchase price
,3602.6:Documenting and reporting repurchases
,3602.7:Survival of Freddie Mac's remedies; misrepresentations by the Seller or Servicer
,3602.8:Appealing a repurchase request due to violations of selling and origination representations and warranties
,3602.9:Appealing a repurchase request or repurchase alternative issued due to Servicing violations
,3603.1:Termination of Servicing
,3603.2:Transfer
,3603.3:Documents and records
,3603.4:Remittance to Freddie Mac
,3603.5:Outstanding purchase commitments
,3603.6:Termination of the Servicing Contract and related Servicing Contract Rights related to sale of Mortgages by Freddie Mac
,4101.1:The Mortgage application
,4101.2:Home Mortgage Uniform Instruments
,4101.3:Authorized changes to Uniform Instruments
,4101.4:Master Form and Short Form Security Instruments
,"4101.5:Origination and delivery of Mortgages using a New York Consolidation, Extension and Modification Agreement (the “NY CEMA”)"
,4101.6:Availability of Uniform Instruments
,4101.7:Seller's duties regarding Uniform Instruments
,4101.8:Signatures required
,"4101.9:Execution, acknowledgment and recordation of the Security Instrument"
,4101.10:Due-on-sale provisions
,4101.11:Advances
,4201.1:Investment quality Mortgage
,4201.2:Mortgage valid First Lien; no prior liens; Mortgage not modified
,4201.3:Amortization
,4201.4:Term
,4201.5:Closed Mortgages and Settlement Date requirements
,4201.6:Principal amount advanced; no mandatory future advances; outstanding balance
,4201.7:Mortgage not in default
,4201.8:Assumption of Mortgage
,4201.9:Biweekly Mortgages and payment plans
,4201.10:Wholesale Home Mortgages
,4201.11:Location of the Mortgaged Premises
,4201.12:General property insurance requirements
,4201.13:No circumstances adversely affecting value of Mortgage
,4201.14:Mortgages secured by Primary Residences
,4201.15:Second home Mortgages
,4201.16:Investment Property Mortgages
,4201.17:Purchase requirements for Mortgages secured by properties with resale restrictions
,4201.18:Impact of Contaminated Sites
,4201.19:Legal description requirements
,4201.20:Blanket Mortgages
,4201.21:Land Trusts
,4201.22:Cooperative Share Loans
,4201.23:Escrow accounts
,4202.1:Compliance with law
,4202.2:State anti-predatory lending laws and regulations
,4202.3:Predatory lending practices
,4202.4:HOEPA Mortgages
,4202.5:Higher-Priced Mortgage Loans and Higher-Priced Covered Transactions
,4202.6:ATR/QM Rule eligibility and compliance
,4202.7:Credit insurance
,4202.8:Mortgages with private transfer fee covenants
,4202.9:Mandatory arbitration
,4203.1:Value
,"4203.2:Calculating LTV, TLTV and HTLTV ratios"
,4203.3:Maximum original loan amounts for Home Mortgage purchases
,"4203.4:Maximum LTV, TLTV and HTLTV ratios"
,4204.1:Mortgages with secondary financing
,4204.2:Affordable Seconds®
,4204.3:Interested party contributions
,4204.4:Temporary subsidy buydown plans
,4204.5:Shared equity plans
,4205.1:Section 502 GRH Mortgages
,4205.2:Home Possible® Mortgages with RHS Leveraged Seconds
,4205.3:Section 184 Native American Mortgages
,4205.4:FHA/VA Mortgages
,4205.5:Mortgage previously sold to the Government National Mortgage Association (GNMA)
,4301.1:Refinance Mortgages
,4301.2:General requirements for all refinance Mortgages
,4301.3:Refinance practices
,"4301.4:""No cash-out"" refinance Mortgages"
,4301.5:Cash-out refinance Mortgages
,4301.6:Special purpose cash-out refinance Mortgages
,4301.7:Texas Equity Section 50(a)(6) Mortgages
,4301.8:Refinance of Mortgages secured by properties subject to an energy retrofit loan
,4302.1:Purchase of Refi Possible℠ Mortgages
,4302.2:Acceptable refinance practices
,4302.3:Eligibility requirements for the Mortgage being refinanced
,4302.4:Borrower eligibility
,4302.5:Special eligibility and underwriting requirements for Refi Possible℠
,4302.6:Credit enhancements
,4302.7:Delivery and pooling
,4302.8:Credit Fees
,4303.1:Freddie Mac Relief Refinance Mortgages℠ — Open Access
,"4303.2:Freddie Mac Relief Refinance Mortgages℠ — Open Access: Eligibility requirements, eligible Mortgages and ineligible Mortgages"
,4303.3:Requirements for Freddie Mac Relief Refinance Mortgages℠ — Open Access
,4303.4:Delivery and pooling requirements for Freddie Mac Relief Refinance Mortgages℠ — Open Access
,4303.5:Credit Fees in Price and other assessments and credits for Freddie Mac Relief Refinance Mortgages℠ — Open Access
,4303.6:Other Guide provisions related to Freddie Mac Relief Refinance Mortgages℠ — Open Access
,4304.1:General eligibility requirements for Enhanced Relief Refinance® Mortgages
,4304.2:Underwriting Enhanced Relief Refinance® Mortgages
,"4304.3:Minimum and maximum LTV, TLTV and HTLTV ratios for Enhanced Relief Refinance® Mortgages"
,4304.4:Borrower eligibility for Enhanced Relief Refinance® Mortgages
,4304.5:Additional underwriting requirements for certain Enhanced Relief Refinance® Mortgages
,4304.6:Incentives and contributions for Enhanced Relief Refinance® Mortgages
,4304.7:Property eligibility and valuation for Enhanced Relief Refinance® Mortgages
,4304.8:Mortgage insurance and credit enhancements for Enhanced Relief Refinance® Mortgages
,4304.9:Cash adjustor under fixed-rate Cash for Freddie Mac Enhanced Relief Refinance® Mortgages
,4305.1:General requirements for all purchase transaction Mortgages
,4401.1:Eligible ARMs
,4401.2:Eligible ARM products
,4401.3:Eligible ARM Index and Lookback Period
,4401.4:General ARM requirements
,4401.5:ARM Note Rate change requirements
,4401.6:Mortgage insurance requirements for ARMs
,4401.7:Title insurance requirements for ARMs
,4401.8:Underwriting requirements for ARMs
,4401.9:Credit Fees for ARMs
,4402.1:Common requirements for Seller-Owned Converted and Seller-Owned Modified Mortgages
,4402.2:Special requirements for Seller-Owned Converted Mortgages
,4402.3:Uniform Instruments and nonstandard documents for Seller-Owned Converted Mortgages
,4402.4:Special requirements for Seller-Owned Modified Mortgages
,4402.5:Uniform Instruments for Seller-Owned Modified Mortgages
,4403.1:Mortgages with capitalized balances
,4404.1:Land contract; contract for deed
,4405.1:Energy conservation improvements
,4406.1:General requirements
,4406.2:Special requirements for all Mortgages secured by properties subject to income-based resale restrictions
,4407.1:Eligibility of properties impacted by a disaster
,4407.2:Representation and warranty relief for automated collateral evaluation appraisal waiver offers and Loan Collateral Advisor®
,4407.3:Age of documentation and Loan Product Advisor® submission requirements in Eligible Disaster areas
,4408.1:Eligibility of Mortgages made pursuant to employee relocation programs
,4408.2:Special occupancy requirement for Mortgages made pursuant to employee relocation programs
,4408.3:Special underwriting requirements for Mortgages made pursuant to employee relocation programs
,4408.4:Special documentation requirements for Mortgages made pursuant to employee relocation programs
,4408.5:Special pooling and delivery requirements for Mortgages made pursuant to employee relocation programs that meet the definition of a relocation Mortgage
,4501.1:Purchase of Home Possible® Mortgages
,4501.2:Home Possible Advantage® Mortgages
,4501.3:Eligible and ineligible Home Possible® Mortgages
,4501.4:Loan purpose for Home Possible® Mortgages
,4501.5:Temporary subsidy buydown plans for Home Possible® Mortgages
,4501.6:Eligible property and appraisal requirements for Home Possible® Mortgages
,4501.7:Eligible Borrowers for Home Possible® Mortgages
,4501.8:Underwriting requirements for Home Possible® Mortgages
,4501.9:Borrower income and qualifying ratios for Home Possible® Mortgages
,"4501.10:LTV/TLTV/HTLTV ratios, Borrower contribution, reserves, sources of funds for Home Possible® Mortgages"
,4501.11:Mortgage insurance for Home Possible® Mortgages
,4501.12:Homeownership education and landlord education for Home Possible® Mortgages
,4501.13:Delivery and pooling for Home Possible® Mortgages
,4501.14:Credit Fees for Home Possible® Mortgages
,4502.1:Overview
,4502.2:Eligible Borrowers for Community Land Trust Mortgages
,4502.3:Eligible and ineligible Community Land Trust Mortgages
,4502.4:Loan purpose for Community Land Trust Mortgages
,4502.5:Eligible property and occupancy types for Community Land Trust Mortgages
,4502.6:Underwriting requirements for Community Land Trust Mortgages
,4502.7:Maximum LTV/TLTV/HTLTV ratios and value for Community Land Trust Mortgages
,4502.8:Appraisal requirements for Community Land Trust Mortgages
,4502.9:Community Land Trust eligibility requirements
,4502.10:Requirements for Community Land Trust Ground Lease and Ground Lease Rider
,4502.11:Security Instruments for Community Land Trust Mortgages
,4502.12:Title insurance requirements for Community Land Trust Mortgages
,4502.13:Other requirements for Community Land Trust Mortgages
,4502.14:Landlord education
,4503.1:Shared Equity Programs – Resale Restrictions
,4504.1:Purchase of HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,4504.2:Overview of HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,4504.3:Eligible Borrowers for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,4504.4:Ineligible Mortgages
,4504.5:General eligibility requirements for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,"4504.6:Underwriting requirements, qualifying ratios and maximum LTV/TLTV ratios for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages"
,"4504.7:Borrower contributions and reserves, and source of funds for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages"
,4504.8:HeritageOne℠ Mortgages that are leasehold Mortgages
,4504.9:Appraisal requirements for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,4504.10:Mortgage insurance for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,4504.11:Credit Fees for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,4504.12:Title insurance requirements for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,4504.13:Mortgage file requirements for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,4601.1:Eligible Financed Permanent Buydown Mortgages
,4601.2:Underwriting Financed Permanent Buydown Mortgages
,4601.3:Other requirements for Financed Permanent Buydown Mortgages
,4602.1:Replacement of Interim Construction Financing overview
,4602.2:Eligible and ineligible Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,4602.3:Documentation of Permanent Financing
,4602.4:Mortgage term for Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,4602.5:Mortgage purpose for Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,4602.6:Eligible Borrowers for Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,4602.7:Eligible property for Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,4602.8:Underwriting the Permanent Financing
,4602.9:Appraisal requirements for Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,4602.10:Calculation of value for Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,4602.11:Seller-Owned Modified and Seller-Owned Converted Mortgages
,4602.12:Mortgage file documentation for Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,4602.13:Residential loan application and uniform underwriting and transmittal summary forms for Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,4602.14:Delivery requirements for Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,4602.15:Credit Fees for Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,4603.1:Purchase of super conforming Mortgages
,4603.2:Minimum and maximum original loan amounts for super conforming Mortgages
,4603.3:General eligibility requirements for super conforming Mortgages
,4603.4:Underwriting requirements for super conforming Mortgages
,4603.5:Appraisal requirements for super conforming Mortgages
,4603.6:Delivery and pooling requirements for super conforming Mortgages
,4603.7:Credit Fees for super conforming Mortgages
,4604.1:Purchase of Affordable Merit Rate® Mortgages
,4604.2:Eligible Affordable Merit Rate® Mortgages
,4604.3:Special underwriting requirements for Affordable Merit Rate® Mortgages
,4604.4:Other requirements for Affordable Merit Rate® Mortgages
,4605.1:Purchase of HomeOne® Mortgages
,4605.2:Eligibility and delivery for HomeOne® Mortgages
,4606.1:Eligible Mortgages and eligible properties
,4606.2:Determination of value for LTV/TLTV/HTLTV ratios
,4606.3:Monthly housing expense-to-income ratio and monthly debt payment-to-income ratio
,"4606.4:Purchase and ""no cash-out"" refinance Mortgage requirements"
,4606.5:Basic energy and water efficiency improvements
,4606.6:Energy reports
,4606.7:Transfers of Servicing
,4606.8:Delivery requirements and credit for Credit Fees
,4607.1:Purchase of CHOICERenovation® Mortgages
,4607.2:Eligible and ineligible Mortgages
,4607.3:Property eligibility and occupancy
,4607.4:General eligibility requirements
,4607.5:Underwriting CHOICERenovation® Mortgages
,4607.6:Eligible renovations
,4607.7:Advancing the cost of materials
,4607.8:Maximum financed renovation costs for CHOICERenovation® Mortgages
,4607.9:Appraisal requirements for CHOICERenovation® Mortgages
,4607.10:Seller responsibilities for renovation work and process
,4607.11:Contractors
,4607.12:Funds for renovations and contingency reserve requirements
,4607.13:Custodial Accounts for Renovation Funds
,4607.14:Property insurance
,4607.15:Recourse
,4607.16:Representations and warranties for CHOICERenovation® Mortgages
,4607.17:Delivery requirements for CHOICERenovation® Mortgages and credit for Credit Fees
,4607.18:Transfers of Servicing
,4701.1:Mortgage insurance
,4701.2:Mortgage insurance premiums
,"4701.3:Commissions, fees or other compensation on insurance"
,4701.4:Late charges
,4701.5:Mortgage insurance for Cooperative Share Loans
,4702.1:General Freddie Mac title insurance requirements
,4702.2:Title insurance policy requirements
,4702.3:Opinions of title (certificates of title)
,4702.4:Acceptable exceptions to the title insurance policy or to the attorney's opinion of title
,4702.5:Special title insurance requirements for Texas Equity Section 50(a)(6) Mortgages
,4702.6:Title insurance requirements for Cooperative Projects and Cooperative Share Loans
,4702.7:Title insurance requirements for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,4703.1:General property insurance requirements
,4703.2:Minimum property insurance types and amounts
,4703.3:Flood insurance
,4703.4:Liability insurance for Condominium Projects and Cooperative Projects
,4703.5:Fidelity or employee dishonesty insurance for Condominium Project and Cooperative Projects
,4703.6:Mortgage clause
,4703.7:Localized perils insurance
,5101.1:General information for using Loan Product Advisor®
,5101.2:Accuracy of data submitted to Loan Product Advisor®
,5101.3:Loan Product Advisor® Risk Class
,5101.4:Documentation requirements when using Loan Product Advisor®
,5101.5:Property and appraisal feedback messages
,5101.6:Resubmission requirements/Loan Product Advisor® tolerances
,5101.7:Resubmission to Loan Product Advisor® after the Note Date
,5101.8:Representation and warranty relief for creditworthiness
,5101.9:A-minus Mortgages
,5102.1:Underwriting a Mortgage
,5102.2:Methods of underwriting
,5102.3:General requirements for verifying documents
,5102.4:Age of documentation
,5103.1:Mortgages including a non-occupying Borrower
,5103.2:Permanent and nonpermanent resident aliens
,"5103.3:Endorser, guarantor and surety"
,5103.4:Creditworthiness of a previous Borrower
,5103.5:Living Trust
,5103.6:Homeownership education
,5103.7:Land Trust
,5103.8:Parent or disabled child occupying the Mortgaged Premises
,5201.1:Credit assessment with Loan Product Advisor®
,5202.1:Establishing Borrower credit reputation for Manually Underwritten Mortgages
,5202.2:Documenting Borrower credit reputation for Manually Underwritten Mortgages
,5202.3:Evaluating Borrower credit reputation for Manually Underwritten Mortgages
,5202.4:Additional requirements for Borrowers with usable Credit Scores
,5202.5:Adverse or derogatory credit information
,5202.6:Evaluating other credit information
,5203.1:Credit reports
,5203.2:Credit Scores
,5301.1:General requirements for all stable monthly income
,5301.2:General requirements for all stable monthly asset qualification sources
,5301.3:Note Date references
,5302.1:Introduction to documentation requirements
,5302.2:Employed income documentation and verification requirements
,5302.3:Third-party verification service providers: employment and income verifications
,5302.4:Tax returns and tax return information: Documentation and verification requirements
,5302.5:IRS Form 4506-C requirements for all income and asset qualification sources
,5303.1:General requirements for all employed income
,5303.2:Primary and secondary employment and income
,5303.3:Additional employed income
,5303.4:Employed income calculation guidance and requirements
,5303.5:Income while on temporary leave
,5304.1:Stable monthly income and documentation requirements for self-employed Borrowers
,5305.1:General requirements for all other income (non-employment/non-self-employment)
,5305.2:Specific requirements for other income types
,5306.1:Rental income overview
,5306.2:Rental income from live-in aide residing in a 1-unit Primary Residence
,5306.3:Rental income generated from an ADU on a subject 1-unit Primary Residence
,"5306.4:Rental income from a 2- to 4-unit Primary Residence, subject 1- to 4-unit Investment Property and non-subject Investment Property"
,5307.1:Assets as a basis for repayment of obligations
,5401.1:Monthly housing expense-to-income ratio
,5401.2:Monthly debt payment-to-income ratio
,5501.1:Funds required for the Mortgage transaction
,5501.2:Reserves
,5501.3:Asset eligibility and documentation requirements
,5501.4:Employer Assisted Homeownership (EAH) Benefit
,5501.5:Interested party contributions
,5501.6:Seller contributions
,5601.1:Property eligibility requirements
,5601.2:Eligibility of a property with an ADU
,5601.3:Eligibility of a property with incomplete improvements
,5601.4:Eligibility of properties with energy efficient improvements and properties with solar panels
,5601.5:Eligibility of a property with mixed-use
,5601.6:Eligibility of a property with two or more adjoining parcels
,5601.7:Overview of appraisal report forms
,"5601.8:Age of appraisal reports and appraisal update requirements, age of automated collateral evaluation offers and re-use of an appraisal report for a subsequent transaction"
,5601.9:Seller representations and warranties regarding the Mortgaged Premises
,5601.10:Required exhibits and addenda for appraisal report forms
,"5601.11:Appraisals completed subject to completion, repairs or alterations, or an inspection"
,5601.12:Property description and analysis
,5601.13:Obtaining subsequent appraisal reports and reconciling multiple opinions of market value
,5601.14:Appraisal data and delivery; Uniform Appraisal Dataset (UAD) and Uniform Collateral Data Portal® (UCDP®)
,5601.15:Electronic transmission of appraisal reports
,5602.1:Collateral representations and warranties
,5602.2:Loan Collateral Advisor®
,5602.3:Automated collateral evaluation (ACE) – appraisal waiver
,"5603.1:Appraiser Independence Requirements, Seller selection of appraisers and appraiser qualifications"
,5603.2:Seller verification of subject property owner of record
,5603.3:Information supplied to the appraiser and Borrower
,5603.4:Unacceptable appraisal practices
,5604.1:Appraisal report forms and inspection types
,5604.2:Exhibits and addenda for appraisal reports
,"5604.3:Age of appraisal reports, appraisal update requirements and re-use of an appraisal report for a subsequent transaction"
,5604.4:Obtaining subsequent appraisal reports and reconciling multiple opinions of market value
,"5605.1:Appraisal report requirements, property description and analysis"
,5605.2:Definition of market value
,"5605.3:Subject property, contract and neighborhood description"
,5605.4:Site and location analysis
,5605.5:Improvements analysis
,5605.6:Sales comparison approach
,"5605.7:Cost and income approaches, and reconciliation"
,"5605.8:Appraisals completed subject to completion, repairs or alterations, or an inspection"
,5605.9:Special property appraisal requirements
,5606.1:Uniform Appraisal Dataset (UAD)
,5606.2:Uniform Collateral Data Portal (UCDP)
,5606.3:Electronic transmission of appraisal reports
,5701.1:Seller's assessment of project risks; terms used in this chapter
,5701.2:Condominium Project review and general Condominium Project eligibility requirements
,5701.3:Ineligible projects
,5701.4:Streamlined reviews
,5701.5:Established Condominium Projects
,5701.6:New Condominium Projects
,5701.7:Exempt From Review
,5701.8:Condominium appraisal and underwriting requirements
,5701.9:Reciprocal project reviews
,5701.10:Condominium Hotel
,5701.11:Projects with excessive commercial or non-residential space
,5701.12:Delivery requirements
,5702.1:Requirements for Planned Unit Developments (PUDs)
,5702.2:Seller warranties for Planned Unit Developments (PUDs)
,5702.3:Appraisal requirements for units in Planned Unit Developments (PUDs)
,5702.4:Reciprocal project reviews for Planned Unit Developments (PUDs)
,5703.1:Purchase of Mortgages secured by Manufactured Homes
,5703.2:Property eligibility for Manufactured Homes
,5703.3:General eligibility requirements for Mortgages secured by Manufactured Homes
,5703.4:Eligible transaction types for Mortgages secured by Manufactured Homes
,5703.5:Underwriting requirements for Mortgages secured by Manufactured Homes
,5703.6:Appraisal requirements for Manufactured Homes
,5703.7:Title issues and lien requirements relating to Manufactured Homes
,5703.8:Taxation of Mortgaged Premises
,5703.9:Mortgages secured by a CHOICEHome®
,5703.10:Other requirements for Mortgages secured by Manufactured Homes
,5704.1:Purchase of leasehold Mortgages
,5704.2:Projects on leasehold estates
,5704.3:Appraisal requirements for leasehold Mortgages
,5704.4:Ground lease requirements for leasehold Mortgages
,5704.5:Security Instruments for leasehold Mortgages
,5705.1:Cooperative Share Loans
,5705.2:Cooperative Project review and general Cooperative Project eligibility requirements
,5705.3:Ineligible Cooperative Projects
,5705.4:Cooperative Project eligibility
,5705.5:Cooperative Share Loan eligibility
,5705.6:Legal requirements for New Cooperative Projects
,5705.7:Exempt From Review
,5705.8:Appraisal requirements for Cooperative Units
,5705.9:Combined Cooperative Units
,5705.10:Cooperative Project Conversions
,5705.11:Documents to be delivered to the Document Custodian and other documents to be maintained by Seller
,5705.12:Pooling and delivery requirements for Cooperative Share Loans
,5706.1:Purchase of Mortgages secured by Manufactured Homes on leasehold estates
,5706.2:Property eligibility for Mortgages secured by Manufactured Homes on leasehold estates
,5706.3:Lease provisions
,5706.4:Value of leasehold estates
,5706.5:Underwriting requirements for Mortgages secured by Manufactured Homes on leasehold estates
,5706.6:Eligible transaction types for Mortgages secured by Manufactured Homes on leasehold estates
,5706.7:Title issues and lien requirements relating to Manufactured Homes on leasehold estates
,5801.1:Uniform Closing Dataset and Loan Closing Advisor®
,5901.1:Automated income assessment with Loan Product Advisor® using employer data overview
,5901.2:Automated income assessment with Loan Product Advisor® using employer data eligibility requirements
,5901.3:Third-party verification service providers and income verification reports
,5901.4:Loan Product Advisor® requirements
,5901.5:Representation and warranty relief and additional requirements
,5902.1:Automated asset assessment with Loan Product Advisor® using account data overview
,5902.2:Automated asset assessment with Loan Product Advisor® using account data eligibility requirements
,5902.3:Verification reports
,5902.4:Loan Product Advisor® requirements and assessment results
,5902.5:Representation and warranty relief
,5902.6:Asset verification and documentation requirements
,5902.7:Seller's in-house quality control program
,5903.1:Automated income assessment with Loan Product Advisor® using tax return data overview
,5903.2:Automated income assessment with Loan Product Advisor® using tax return data eligibility requirements
,5903.3:Income Calculation Report generation and underwriting requirements
,5903.4:Loan Product Advisor® requirements
,5903.5:Representation and warranty relief and additional requirements
,5903.6:Documentation requirements
,5904.1:Automated income assessment with Loan Product Advisor® using account data overview
,5904.2:Automated income assessment with Loan Product Advisor® using account data – eligibility requirements
,5904.3:Verification reports
,5904.4:Loan Product Advisor® requirements
,5904.5:Representation and warranty relief and additional requirements
,5904.6:Delivery requirements
,5905.1:Automated employment assessment with Loan Product Advisor® using account data overview
,5905.2:Automated employment assessment with using account data eligibility requirements
,5905.3:Verification reports
,5905.4:Automated assessment results
,6101.1:Eligible Sellers for fixed-rate Cash
,6101.2:Mortgages eligible under fixed-rate Cash
,6101.3:Mandatory fixed-rate Cash Contracts
,6101.4:Best Efforts Contracts under fixed-rate Cash
,6101.5:Purchase and settlement of Mandatory fixed-rate Cash and Best Efforts fixed-rate Cash Contracts
,6101.6:Servicing options for Mandatory fixed-rate Cash and Best Efforts fixed-rate Cash Contracts
,6101.7:Requirements for fixed-rate Cash Contracts through Cash-Released XChange®
,6101.8:Pricing under Fixed-rate Cash
,6102.1:Eligible Sellers for ARM Cash
,6102.2:ARM Cash defined terms
,6102.3:Eligible ARMs and purchase requirements for ARM Cash
,6102.4:ARM Cash Contracts
,6102.5:Pricing under ARM Cash
,6102.6:Acceptance of offer under ARM Cash
,6102.7:Servicing options for ARM Cash
,6102.8:Remittance cycle and Servicing Spreads for ARM Cash Contracts
,6102.9:Purchase and settlement under ARM Cash Contracts
,6103.1:Establishing a securities trading account with Freddie Mac
,6201.1:Summary of Guarantor and MultiLender Swap programs
,6201.2:Sellers eligible to submit offers under the Guarantor and MultiLender Swap programs
,6201.3:Purchase requirements for Mortgages sold under the Guarantor and MultiLender Swap programs
,6201.4:MultiLender Swap posting information
,6201.5:Review of Mortgages for compliance with Seller's Maximum Annual Mortgage Purchase Amount
,"6201.6:Freddie Mac's obligation to sell UMBS™, MBS, ARM PCs or Supers™ in exchange for Mortgages"
,6201.7:Seller's election to sell with or without recourse under the Guarantor and MultiLender Swap programs
,6201.8:Remittance cycles under the Guarantor and MultiLender Swap programs
,6201.9:Guarantor Pricing
,6201.10:Buyup and buydown programs under the fixed-rate Guarantor and MultiLender Swap programs
,6201.11:Security wire instructions for the Guarantor and MultiLender Swap programs
,6201.12:Settlement under the Guarantor and MultiLender Swap programs
,6201.13:Special Seller representations and warranties under the Guarantor and MultiLender Swap programs
,6201.14:Postsettlement adjustments for Mortgages purchased under the Guarantor and MultiLender Swap programs
,"6201.15:UMBS™, MBS, ARM PCs, Supers™ and pool factors"
,"6201.16:Disclosure requirements for UMBS™, MBS, ARM PCs and Supers™"
,"6201.17:Indemnification for liability relating to Seller's sale of UMBS™, MBS, ARM PCs and Supers™"
,"6201.18:UMBS™, MBS, ARM PC and Supers™ delivery"
,6201.19:Freddie Mac remedies for Seller's breach of representations and warranties relating to securitized loans
,6202.1:Freddie Mac Swap disclosure and pooling requirements
,"6202.2:Freddie Mac UMBS®, MBS, Supers® and WAC ARM PC disclosure"
,6202.3:Pooling requirements for UMBS® and MBS Pools and Supers® Pools
,6202.4:Pooling requirements for WAC ARM PC Pools
,6203.1:Eligible Sellers for the fixed-rate Guarantor program through Loan Selling Advisor®
,6203.2:Eligible Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the fixed-rate Guarantor program
,6203.3:Purchase requirements for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the fixed-rate Guarantor program
,6203.4:Offer procedures/amounts/optional delivery/contract cancelation for Fixed-Rate Guarantor Contracts
,6203.5:Purchase and sale obligations and Commitment Amounts for Fixed-Rate Guarantor Contracts
,6203.6:Providing data for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the fixed-rate Guarantor program
,6203.7:Remittance cycle and Servicing Spreads for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the fixed-rate Guarantor program
,6203.8:Wire transfer instructions/delivery of UMBS® and MBS for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the fixed-rate Guarantor program
,6203.9:Loan Purchase Statements and UMBS™ and MBS disclosure for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the fixed-rate Guarantor program
,6204.1:Eligible Sellers for the WAC ARM Guarantor program through Loan Selling Advisor®
,6204.2:Eligible ARMs sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the WAC ARM Guarantor program
,6204.3:Purchase requirements for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the WAC ARM Guarantor program
,6204.4:Offer procedures/amounts/optional delivery/contract cancelation for WAC ARM Guarantor Contracts
,6204.5:Purchase and sale obligations and Commitment Amounts for WAC ARM Guarantor Contracts
,6204.6:Providing data for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the WAC ARM Guarantor program
,6204.7:Remittance cycle and Servicing Spreads for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the WAC ARM Guarantor program
,6204.8:Wire transfer instructions/delivery of ARM PCs for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the WAC ARM Guarantor program
,6204.9:Loan Purchase Statements and ARM PC disclosure for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the WAC ARM Guarantor program
,6205.1:Eligible Sellers for the MultiLender Swap program through Loan Selling Advisor®
,6205.2:Eligible fixed-rate Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the MultiLender Swap program
,6205.3:Purchase and pooling requirements for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the MultiLender Swap program
,6205.4:Offer procedures/amounts/optional delivery/contract cancelation for MultiLender Swap Contracts
,6205.5:Purchase and sale obligations and Commitment Amounts for MultiLender Swap Contracts
,6205.6:Providing data for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the MultiLender Swap program
,"6205.7:Remittance cycle, Credit Fee in Yield and Servicing Spread for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the MultiLender Swap program"
,"6205.8:Wire transfer instructions/delivery of UMBS®, MBS and Supers® for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the MultiLender Swap program"
,6205.9:Loan Purchase Statements and UMBS®/MBS/Supers® disclosure for Mortgages sold through Loan Selling Advisor® under the MultiLender Swap program
,6301.1:Home Mortgage documentation delivery
,6301.2:Pledged Mortgage delivery
,6301.3:Endorsement of Notes
,6301.4:Power of attorney
,6301.5:Modifying instrument or assumption of indebtedness agreement
,6301.6:Assignment of Security Instrument
,6301.7:Accuracy and preparation of Mortgage data submitted
,6301.8:Completion of delivery
,6301.9:Mortgage substitutions
,6301.10:Purchase and settlement procedures
,6301.11:Postsettlement purchase adjustments
,6302.1:Organization of delivery instructions for ULDD Data Points
,6302.2:Cash program delivery instructions
,6302.3:Guarantor program delivery instructions
,6302.4:MultiLender Swap program delivery instructions
,6302.5:Loan data required for all Mortgages
,6302.6:Loan data required for fixed-rate Mortgages
,6302.7:Loan data required for ARMs
,6302.8:Property data required for all Mortgages
,6302.9:Data required for all Borrowers
,6302.10:Loan Product Advisor® Mortgage underwriting data delivery requirements
,6302.11:Non-Loan Product Advisor® Mortgage data delivery requirements
,6302.12:Special delivery requirements for FHA/VA Mortgages
,6302.13:Special delivery requirements for Section 184 Native American Mortgages
,6302.14:Special delivery requirements for Home Possible® Mortgages
,6302.15:Special delivery requirements for Section 502 GRH Mortgages
,6302.16:Special delivery requirements for refinance Mortgages
,6302.17:Special delivery requirements for fixed-rate relocation Mortgages
,6302.18:Special delivery requirements for subsidy buydown Mortgages
,6302.19:Special delivery requirements for Seller-Owned Converted Mortgages
,6302.20:Special delivery requirements for Condominium Unit Mortgages
,6302.21:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages with mortgage insurance
,6302.22:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages with capitalized balances
,6302.23:Special delivery requirements for GreenCHOICE Mortgages®
,6302.24:Special delivery requirements for Financed Permanent Buydown Mortgages
,6302.25:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages secured by Manufactured Homes
,6302.26:Special delivery requirements for fixed-rate Mortgages sold through Cash-Released XChange®
,6302.27:Special delivery requirements for Seller-Owned Modified Mortgages
,6302.28:Special delivery requirements for Construction Conversion and Renovation Mortgages
,6302.29:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages with Employer Assisted Homeownership (EAH) Benefits
,"6302.30:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages where Borrower uses credit card, cash advance or unsecured line of credit to pay fees"
,6302.31:Special delivery requirements for super conforming Mortgages
,6302.32:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages with principal curtailments
,6302.33:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages in which assets are used as a basis for repayment of obligations
,6302.34:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages with secondary financing
,6302.35:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages eligible for sale using the loan-level buyup and buydown program
,6302.36:Special delivery requirements for Affordable Merit Rate® Mortgages
,6302.37:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages secured by properties with resale restrictions
,6302.38:Special delivery requirements for Pledged Mortgages
,6302.39:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages with special attributes designated for cash specified pools
,6302.40:Special delivery requirements for Freddie Mac Enhanced Relief Refinance® Mortgages
,6302.41:Special delivery requirements for HomeOne® Mortgages
,6302.42:Special delivery requirements for Community Land Trust Mortgages
,6302.43:Special delivery requirements for CHOICERenovation® Mortgages
,6302.44:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages utilizing the age of documentation flexibility in Eligible Disaster Areas
,6302.45:Special delivery requirements for Cooperative Share Loans
,6302.46:Special delivery requirements for Refi Possible®Mortgages
,6302.47:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages with title insurance
,6302.48:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages originated in rural areas and by Small Financial Institutions
,6302.49:Special delivery requirements for Mortgages located in rural areas in High Needs Rural Regions
,6302.50:Special delivery requirements for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,6303.1:Assessment of fees
,6303.2:Payment of fees
,"6303.3:Refunds, repayments, credits and adjustments of Credit Fees"
,6303.4:Fee for Purchase Contracts that exceed the Maximum Annual Mortgage Purchase Amount
,6303.5:Recapture of premiums and reimbursement of buyup proceeds
,6303.6:Late payment policy
,6304.1:Custody of Notes and assignments
,6304.2:Delivery of Notes and assignments to a Document Custodian
,6304.3:Document Custodian's functions and duties upon receiving Notes and assignments
,6305.1:Warehouse financing arrangements
,6305.2:Delivery and acceptance of Pledged Mortgages
,6305.3:Wire transfer instructions for Pledged Mortgages sold for cash
,"6305.4:UMBS®, MBS and WAC ARM PC delivery instructions for Pledged Mortgages"
,6305.5:Delivery procedures for Pledged Mortgages
,6305.6:Acceptance for purchase or rejection of Pledged Mortgages
,6305.7:Warehouse Lender's interest
,6305.8:Seller representations and warranties for Pledged Mortgages
,6305.9:Liability for a postponed Settlement Date for Pledged Mortgages
,6305.10:Seller indemnification
,6305.11:Reimbursement by the Seller for Pledged Mortgages
,6305.12:Special Warehouse Lender acknowledgments and agreements
,6306.1:Correspondent XChange®
,6401.1:Pairoff
,6401.2:Penalty for nondelivery
,7101.1:Transfers of Servicing overview
,7101.2:Submitting requests for Transfers of Servicing and Intra-Servicer Portfolio Moves
,7101.3:Review of Transferor Servicer and Transferee Servicer
,7101.4:Additional conditions for Transfers of Servicing
,7101.5:Requirements for reporting Transfers of Servicing to Freddie Mac
,7101.6:Endorsement of Notes and assignment of Security Instruments for Mortgages related to Transfers of Servicing
,7101.7:Concurrent or Subsequent Transfers of Servicing for a Mortgage secured by a Manufactured Home located in a certificate of title State
,7101.8:Transfer of records
,7101.9:Document custody requirements for Transfers of Servicing
,7101.10:Transfer of funds
,7101.11:Notice to Borrowers regarding Transfers of Servicing
,7101.12:Borrower issues and inquiries related to Transfers of Servicing
,7101.13:Funds and correspondence received after Transfers of Servicing
,7101.14:Notices of Transfers of Servicing to third parties
,7101.15:Liabilities of the Transferor Servicer and Transferee Servicer
,7102.1:Overview
,7102.2:VPC Transfer of Servicing and Flow VPC Transfer of Servicing
,8101.1:Servicers' general responsibilities
,8101.2:The Servicer to perform its obligations and duties at its own expense
,8101.3:Servicer's limited power of attorney
,8101.4:Servicer's execution of documents
,8101.5:Borrower inquiries
,8101.6:Error resolution procedures related to the Servicing of a Mortgage
,8101.7:Freddie Mac audits and access to Mortgage records
,8101.8:Treatment of personal and property information
,8101.9:Servicer agrees to indemnify
,8101.10:Servicer as independent contractor
,8101.11:Governing law
,8101.12:MERS®
,8102.1:Managing Servicing Agents
,8102.2:Obligations upon termination or expiration of Subservicing Agreement
,8103.1:Servicer fiscal responsibilities
,8103.2:Mortgage accounting records
,8103.3:Accounting methods
,8103.4:Application of payments: general
,8103.5:Application of payments: differences in collection
,8103.6:Application of payments: Mortgage paid in full
,8103.7:Application of payments: partial prepayments (curtailments)
,8103.8:Reapplication of prior repayments
,8103.9:Accounting with respect to delinquency relief
,8104.1:Servicing Texas Equity Section 50(a)(6) Mortgages
,8104.2:Biweekly payment plans
,"8104.3:FHA, VA, RHS and MI Servicing requirements"
,8104.4:Servicing ARMs
,8104.5:Home Mortgages purchased in part
,8104.6:Incomplete improvements
,8104.7:Servicing eMortgages
,8104.8:Servicing Community Land Trust Mortgages
,8104.9:Servicing Mortgages secured by properties subject to resale restrictions
,8104.10:Right of first refusal
,8104.11:Servicing Cooperative Share Loans
,8105.1:Compensation for Servicing Mortgages
,8105.2:Servicing compensation for a new Servicer pursuant to Transfer of Servicing initiated by Freddie Mac
,8105.3:Servicing obligations to be performed for the Servicing compensation
,"8106.1:General requirements for Servicing-related reports to Freddie Mac, third parties and the Borrower"
,"8106.2:IRS Form 1098, Mortgage Interest Statement"
,"8106.3:IRS Form 1099-A, Acquisition or Abandonment of Secured Property"
,"8106.4:IRS Form 1099-C, Cancellation of Debt"
,"8106.5:IRS Form 1099-MISC, Miscellaneous Income"
,8106.6:Reports to credit repositories
,8107.1:Servicer responsibilities related to document custody
,8107.2:Document Custodian's custodial functions
,"8201.1:Escrow for property taxes, ground rents and assessments or other charges"
,8201.2:Interest on Escrow accounts
,8202.1:General property insurance requirements
,8202.2:Minimum property insurance types and amounts
,8202.3:Flood insurance
,8202.4:Rent loss insurance
,8202.5:Liability insurance for Condominium Projects and Cooperative Projects
,8202.6:Fidelity or employee dishonesty insurance for Condominium Projects and Cooperative Projects
,8202.7:Mortgage clause
,8202.8:Evidence of insurance
,8202.9:Insurance charges
,8202.10:Localized perils insurance
,8202.11:Insurance loss settlements
,8202.12:Lender-Placed Insurance
,"8203.1:Mortgage insurance terms, warranties and other requirements"
,8203.2:Borrower-requested cancelation of Borrower-paid mortgage insurance on an HPA Mortgage
,8203.3:Borrower-requested cancelation of Borrower-paid mortgage insurance on a Non-HPA Mortgage
,8203.4:Automatic cancelation of Borrower-paid mortgage insurance on an HPA Mortgage
,8203.5:Cancelation of Borrower-paid mortgage insurance on modified Mortgages
,8203.6:Cancelation of Borrower-paid mortgage insurance on reset Mortgages
,8203.7:Cancelation of Borrower-paid mortgage insurance on refinance Mortgages
,8203.8:Cancelation of lender-paid mortgage insurance
,8203.9:FHA insurance
,8203.10:Transfers of mortgage insurance coverage
,8203.11:Reporting mortgage insurance cancelations
,8203.12:Directing MI disclosure of Mortgage information to Freddie Mac and reconciliation
,8301.1:Servicer's responsibilities in connection with Mortgage-Backed Securities and Participation Certificates
,8301.2:Investor accounting responsibilities
,8301.3:Investor reporting performance standards
,8301.4:Accounting reporting methods
,8301.5:Calculating Mortgage interest due to Freddie Mac
,8301.6:Freddie Mac's percentage of ownership
,8301.7:Net yield interest
,8301.8:Servicing fee
,8301.9:Electronic reporting format
,8301.10:Reporting media
,8301.11:Loan-level transaction
,8301.12:Accounting Cycle
,8301.13:Cash float
,8301.14:Other reporting and remitting requirements
,8301.15:Service bureau liability and notice of change of service bureau
,8301.16:Backup reporting
,8301.17:Administering Custodial Accounts
,8301.18:Custodial Account reconciliation basics
,8301.19:Servicer advances required
,8302.1:Custodial Accounts required
,8302.2:Disbursement clearing accounts
,8302.3:Opening Custodial Accounts
,8302.4:Depository eligibility requirements
,8302.5:Insured depository risk level
,8302.6:Custodial Account and custodial clearing account designation requirements
,8302.7:Custodial Account documentation requirements
,8302.8:Honoring sight drafts
,8302.9:What funds to deposit to the Custodial Accounts
,8302.10:When to deposit funds to the Custodial Accounts
,8302.11:Changing or transferring Custodial Accounts
,8302.12:Administering and reconciling Custodial Accounts
,8302.13:Setting up the automated cash remittance process
,8302.14:Remitting via the automated cash remittance system
,8302.15:Initiating remittances to Freddie Mac
,8302.16:Changing or transferring the drafting account
,8302.17:Transmitting and receiving investor accounting information
,8302.18:Pre-purchase activity
,8302.19:Mortgage purchase
,8302.20:Setting up a Mortgage record
,8302.21:Purchase adjustments
,8302.22:Reporting and remitting on a newly-funded Mortgage
,8303.1:Definitions of terms specific to chapter
,8303.2:Freddie Mac's rights
,8303.3:Reporting and drafting
,8303.4:Monthly reporting and remittance requirements for Mortgages with partial principal forbearance
,8303.5:Correcting reporting errors
,8303.6:Freddie Mac drafting timelines
,8303.7:Availability of funds
,8303.8:Correcting a remittance
,8303.9:Payoff – matured or prepaid reporting and drafting requirements
,8303.10:Third-party foreclosure sale reporting and drafting requirements
,8303.11:Short sale reporting and drafting requirements
,8303.12:Make-whole preforeclosure sale reporting and drafting requirements
,8303.13:Reporting a charge-off
,8303.14:Repurchase reporting and drafting requirements
,8303.15:Loan-level transaction reporting
,8303.16:Monthly reporting and remitting requirements
,8303.17:Quarterly reporting requirements for SCRA interest rate capped Mortgages
,8303.18:Monthly remittance cycle
,8303.19:Draft dates
,"8303.20:Monthly reporting and drafting requirements, including exception activities"
,8303.21:Reporting inactivation of a Mortgage
,8303.22:Newly-funded Mortgage reporting and drafting requirements
,8303.23:Reinstatement
,8303.24:Principal balance correction
,8303.25:Deed-in-lieu of foreclosure reporting and remittance requirements
,8303.26:FHA/VA foreclosure conveyance reporting and drafting requirements
,8303.27:REO reporting and drafting requirements
,8303.28:Additional monthly reporting requirements
,8303.29:Freddie Mac's reports to Servicers of discrepancies
,8303.30:Daily edit reports
,8303.31:Monthly reports provided to Servicer
,8303.32:Reports to reconcile monthly activity
,8303.33:Reconciling Seller/Servicer Remittance Analysis
,8303.34:Noncompliance with reporting and drafting requirements
,8303.35:Drafting noncompliance compensatory fees
,8303.36:Reporting noncompliance compensatory fees
,8303.37:Reporting noncompliance compensatory fees – all loans
,8303.38:EDR noncompliance compensatory fees
,8303.39:Unreported transactions and loan simulation compensatory fee
,8303.40:Aged data errors compensatory fee
,8303.41:Next month late reported payoff noncompliance compensatory fee
,8303.42:Draft delay compensatory fee
,8303.43:Contract noncompliance and contract change compensatory fees
,8303.44:Freddie Mac resources related to reporting and remittance
,8304.1:Managing Custodial Accounts
,8304.2:Freddie Mac's rights
,8304.3:Servicer responsibilities related to Custodial Accounts
,8304.4:Investing Custodial Account funds
,8304.5:Maintaining the Principal and Interest Custodial Account balance
,8304.6:Maintaining the Escrow Custodial Account balance
,8304.7:Maintaining the Buydown Custodial Account
,8304.8:Monitoring depository eligibility
,8304.9:Freddie Mac's right to remove accounts from specified depositories
,8304.10:The Servicer's right to change or transfer accounts
,8304.11:Requirements for changing or transferring accounts
,8304.12:Liability for Custodial Account transfer costs
,8304.13:Reconciling Custodial Accounts
,8304.14:Reconciling the Principal and Interest Custodial Account
,8304.15:Freddie Mac's Principal and Interest Custodial Account review
,8304.16:Reconciling deposits to the Principal and Interest Custodial Account
,8304.17:Reconciling withdrawals from the Principal and Interest Custodial Account
,8304.18:Reconciling the Escrow Custodial Account
,8304.19:Freddie Mac's Escrow Custodial Account review
,8304.20:Reconciling deposits to the Escrow Custodial Account
,8304.21:Reconciling withdrawals from the Escrow Custodial Account
,8304.22:Reconciling an optional Custodial Account
,"8401.1:Partial releases, easements and acquisitions"
,8401.2:Prohibition of conversion of the Mortgaged Premises
,8401.3:Condemnation and eminent domain
,"8401.4:Modification, waiver or release of terms"
,8402.1:Property seizure
,8402.2:Unsolicited disclosure of pre-seizure information
,8402.3:Requested disclosure of pre-seizure information
,8402.4:Government notice of property seizure to the Servicer
,8402.5:Government notice of property seizure to Freddie Mac
,8402.6:Reimbursement of expenses related to property seizures
,8403.1:Servicing Mortgages on distressed properties and properties that pose a Risk of Property Ownership
,8403.2:Servicing Mortgages on abandoned properties
,8404.1:Introduction of Servicer responsibilities following a disaster
,8404.2:Property protection activities following a disaster
,8404.3:Insurance loss settlements after an Eligible Disaster
,8404.4:Delinquency management activities following a disaster
,8404.5:Disaster reporting requirements
,8404.6:Transition following disaster-related forbearance
,8405.1:12-month occupancy waiver request
,8406.1:General policy on Transfers of Ownership and assumptions
,8406.2:Transfers of Ownership and assumptions of Mortgages insured by the FHA or guaranteed by the VA or RHS
,8406.3:Federal restrictions on the exercise of the due-on-transfer clause
,8406.4:Additional permitted Transfers of Ownership
,"8406.5:Application for approval of Transfers of Ownership, assumptions and releases of liability"
,"8406.6:Reviewing the application and determining eligibility for Transfers of Ownership, assumptions and releases of liability"
,8406.7:Approval of the application for Transfers of Ownership
,8406.8:Declination of the application for assumption
,8406.9:File retention for Transfers of Ownership and assumptions
,8406.10:Transfer of Ownership fees
,8406.11:Assumability provisions and rate cap requirements for ARMs
,8406.12:Transfers of ownership and buydown accounts
,8501.1:Servicer staff requirements related to Servicing Step-Rate Mortgages
,8501.2:Communicating upcoming interest rate adjustments
,8501.3:Freddie Mac Flex Modification for Step-Rate Mortgages
,8502.1:ARM Servicing and reporting
,8502.2:Rate changes on ARMs
,8502.3:Negative Amortization
,8503.1:Definitions related to Servicing loans of Servicemembers
,8503.2:Relief options exclusive to Servicemembers and their Dependents
,8503.3:Other relief and workout options for Servicemembers and their Dependents
,8503.4:Applying SCRA provisions
,8503.5:Calculation of new monthly payment for SCRA-capped Mortgages
,8503.6:Application of payments on SCRA-capped Mortgages
,8503.7:Accounting reports for SCRA-capped Mortgages
,8503.8:Rate changes on SCRA-capped ARMs
,8503.9:Servicing compensation for SCRA-capped Mortgages
,8503.10:Retroactive rate cap for SCRA-capped Mortgages
,8504.1:Outreach requirements for Mortgages with low interest-bearing UPB and a Deferred Balance that are approaching the Mortgage maturity date or payoff of the interest-bearing UPB
,8601.1:Servicing Senior Subordinate Mortgages
,8601.2:Key terms and definitions used in this chapter
,8601.3:Chapter contents
,"8601.4:Freddie Mac's rights and Servicer rights, duties and obligations"
,8601.5:Limited power of attorney
,8601.6:Requesting a limited power of attorney
,8601.7:Servicer use of Servicing Tools
,8601.8:Borrower inquiries
,"8601.9:IRS Form 1099-A, Acquisition or Abandonment of Secured Property"
,"8601.10:IRS Form 1099-C, Cancellation of Debt"
,"8601.11:IRS Form 1099-MISC, Miscellaneous Income"
,8601.12:Concurrent and Subsequent Transfers of Servicing
,8601.13:Declination of the application for assumption
,8601.14:Modifying Exhibit 93 model letters for Senior Subordinate Mortgages
,8601.15:General requirements for Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters
,8601.16:Referral to foreclosure documentation requirements
,8601.17:Foreclosing in the Servicer's name
,8601.18:Expedited foreclosures
,8601.19:Deficiency rights
,8601.20:Preserving the Mortgaged Premises
,8601.21:Expenses that may become First Liens on the Mortgaged Premises
,8601.22:Delivery of clear and marketable title
,8601.23:Vesting the title and avoiding transfer taxes
,8601.24:Non-routine default-related legal matters
,8601.25:Counsel retained by Servicers pursuant to Servicer's duty to indemnify Freddie Mac
,8601.26:Servicing Mortgages on distressed properties and properties that pose a Risk of Property Ownership
,8601.27:Servicing Mortgages on abandoned properties
,8601.28:Retention of firm
,8601.29:Referral of Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters to firm
,8601.30:REO – General requirements
,8601.31:REO – Documentation and reporting requirements
,8601.32:REO – Notifying the taxing authority/HOA
,8701.1:Servicing Community Land Trust Mortgages
,8701.2:Cancellation of Borrower-paid mortgage insurance
,8701.3:Concurrent and Subsequent Transfers of Servicing with respect to Community Land Trust Mortgages
,8701.4:Delinquency management for Community Land Trust Mortgages
,8801.1:Servicing Cooperative Share Loans
,8801.2:Transfers of Servicing with respect to Cooperative Share Loans
,8801.3:Reduction or cancellation in insurance coverage maintained by the Cooperative Corporation
,8801.4:Cooperative Share Loan expenses that may become First Liens on the property
,8801.5:Loss mitigation for Cooperative Share Loans
,8801.6:Delinquency management for Cooperative Share Loans
,8801.7:Reimbursement of Cooperative Share Loan expenses
,8901.1:Servicing HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,8901.2:Subsequent Transfers of Servicing with respect to HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,8901.3:Delinquency management for HeritageOne℠ Mortgages
,9101.1:Delinquency management for Mortgages secured by Primary Residences
,9101.2:Servicer collection efforts for Mortgages secured by Primary Residences
,9101.3:Evaluation requirements and appeals process in response to the First Complete Borrower Response Package
,9101.4:Foreclosure suspension obligations and additional short sale and deed-in-lieu of foreclosure requirements once the First Complete Borrower Response Package is received
,9102.1:General requirements for Servicing delinquent Mortgages
,9102.2:Late charges
,9102.3:Establishing Borrower contact during Delinquency
,9102.4:Servicer collection efforts
,9102.5:Borrower solicitation and communication
,9102.6:Investment Property and rental income during Delinquency
,9102.7:Monthly EDR
,9102.8:Compensatory fees for failure to report via EDR
,9201.1:Rationale for Servicer loss mitigation activities
,9201.2:Freddie Mac loss mitigation evaluation hierarchy
,9201.3:Servicer's responsibilities for loss mitigation activities
,9201.4:Servicer's loss mitigation operations
,9201.5:Servicer default management performance standards
,9201.6:Alternatives to foreclosure
,"9202.1:Delinquency, default and imminent danger of default"
,9202.2:Verifying a Borrower's hardship
,9202.3:Borrower income documentation for workout or relief options
,9202.4:Servicer reconciliation of inconsistencies; fraud detection; and document authenticity
,9202.5:Risk of Property Ownership
,9202.6:Analyze the reason for Delinquency
,9202.7:Tenant-occupied properties built before 1978
,9202.8:Analyze the Mortgage characteristics and terms
,9202.9:Determine the best course of action for Delinquency
,9202.10:What is a property inspection?
,9202.11:Documenting property inspections
,9202.12:When to order a property inspection
,9202.13:Results of property inspection
,9202.14:What is an abandoned property?
,9202.15:Reimbursement of property inspections
,9202.16:When to obtain a property value
,9202.17:Obtaining a property value
,9202.18:Checking the status of orders for property valuations
,9202.19:Valuation costs
,9202.20:Remitting BPO cost reimbursements to Freddie Mac
,9203.1:Reinstatements and relief options
,9203.2:General requirements for reinstatements and relief options
,9203.3:Types of reinstatement
,9203.4:When to accept full reinstatement
,9203.5:When to accept partial reinstatement of a Mortgage in foreclosure
,9203.6:Reporting and processing the reinstatement
,9203.7:Reimbursement of expenses related to reinstatements
,9203.8:What is a repayment plan?
,9203.9:Repayment plan requirements
,9203.10:Servicer approval authority for repayment plans
,9203.11:Reporting repayment plans
,9203.12:What is forbearance?
,9203.13:Requirements for a forbearance plan
,9203.14:Contact requirements when transitioning from a forbearance plan
,9203.15:Borrowers in a Trial Period Plan
,9203.16:Forbearance plan termination
,9203.17:Other forbearance plan conditions and requirements
,9203.18:What is a Payment Deferral
,9203.19:Servicer approval authority for Payment Deferral
,9203.20:Eligibility requirements for a Payment Deferral
,9203.21:Eligibility exclusions for a Payment Deferral
,9203.22:Determining the terms of a Payment Deferral
,9203.23:Completing Payment Deferral
,9203.24:Submission of Payment Deferral terms and settlement
,9203.25:Other Payment Deferral conditions and requirements
,9203.26:Disaster Payment Deferral
,9203.27:Electronic Payment Deferral Agreements
,9204.1:Freddie Mac workout options
,9204.2:Servicer approval authority for workouts
,9204.3:Freddie Mac's rights related to workout options
,9204.4:Steps for processing a workout recommendation
,9204.5:Borrower documentation for workout options
,9204.6:Servicer compensation for alternatives to foreclosure
,9204.7:Prohibition of certain Borrower fees; non-refusal of workout options due to late charges
,9204.8:Mortgage insurance claims
,9205.1:Home Affordable Modification Program overview
,9205.2:HAMP documentation
,"9205.3:Delegation of authority and HAMP waivers, Supplemental Directives, Frequently Asked Questions and issues logs"
,9205.4:Eligibility for HAMP
,9205.5:Step-Rate Mortgages modified under HAMP
,9205.6:Verification of eligibility for HAMP
,9205.7:Determining imminent default
,9205.8:Underwriting the Borrower for HAMP
,9205.9:Modification process for HAMP
,9205.10:Foreclosure actions and Borrowers in bankruptcy
,9205.11:Transfers of Servicing and document retention requirements
,9205.12:HAMP incentives
,9205.13:Special investor reporting requirements for Mortgages modified under HAMP
,9205.14:HAMP activity reporting requirements
,9205.15:Disclosures and communications with Borrowers
,9205.16:Compliance with applicable law on Mortgages modified under HAMP
,9205.17:Responsiveness to Borrower inquiries
,9205.18:Servicer compliance with HAMP requirements
,9205.19:Special HAMP requirements for Mortgages with a second mortgage lien
,9205.20:HAMP electronic modification
,9205.21:Authorized services under the Amended Servicer Participation Agreement
,9206.1:What is a loan modification?
,9206.2:When to consider a Freddie Mac Flex Modification®
,9206.3:Freddie Mac Streamlined Modification
,9206.4:Capitalization and Extension Modification for Disaster Relief
,9206.5:Eligibility requirements for a Freddie Mac Flex Modification®
,9206.6:Ineligibility for Freddie Mac Flex Modification®
,9206.7:Determining imminent default for a Freddie Mac Flex Modification®
,9206.8:Property valuation requirements for a Freddie Mac Flex Modification®
,9206.9:Borrower Documentation for a Freddie Mac Flex Modification®
,9206.10:Determining the terms of a Freddie Mac Flex Modification®
,9206.11:Trial Period Plan requirements
,9206.12:Modified Mortgage conditions
,9206.13:Other modification conditions and requirements
,9206.14:Loan modification expenses
,"9206.15:Expenses, delinquent amounts, capitalization rules and expense reimbursements for modifications"
,9206.16:Preparing to close the loan modification
,9206.17:Loan modification documents and settlement data submissions
,9206.18:Modification reporting and drafting requirements
,9206.19:Electronic solicitation and modification
,9207.1:What is a workout Mortgage assumption?
,9207.2:When to consider a workout Mortgage assumption
,9207.3:Eligibility requirements for a workout Mortgage assumption
,9207.4:Submitting a workout Mortgage assumption recommendation to Freddie Mac
,9207.5:Freddie Mac's decision about a Servicer's recommendation for workout Mortgage assumption
,9207.6:Approval conditions for a workout Mortgage assumption
,9207.7:Closing requirements for workout Mortgage assumption
,9207.8:Servicer fee for workout Mortgage assumption
,9208.1:What is a short sale?
,9208.2:Short sale eligibility requirements and Servicer approval authority
,9208.3:Borrower documentation for a short sale
,9208.4:Short sale Borrower contributions and relocation assistance
,9208.5:Property valuation and minimum net proceeds for short sales
,9208.6:Communication timelines for short sales
,9208.7:Short sale transaction and processing requirements
,"9208.8:Closing, reporting, drafting and remittance requirements for short sales and make-whole preforeclosure sales"
,9208.9:Fraudulent transactions related to short sales
,9209.1:What is a deed-in-lieu of foreclosure?
,9209.2:Deed-in-lieu of foreclosure eligibility requirements and Servicer approval authority
,9209.3:Borrower documentation for deeds-in-lieu of foreclosure
,9209.4:Deeds-in-lieu of foreclosure Borrower contributions and relocation assistance
,9209.5:Property valuation requirements for deeds-in-lieu of foreclosure
,9209.6:Borrower communication and execution timelines for deeds-in-lieu of foreclosure
,9209.7:Deed-in-lieu of foreclosure transaction and processing requirements
,"9209.8:Closing, reporting and remittance requirements for deeds-in-lieu of foreclosure"
,9210.1:What is a charge-off?
,9210.2:When a Servicer must recommend a charge-off
,9210.3:Submitting a recommendation for a charge-off to Freddie Mac
,9210.4:Freddie Mac's decision about a Servicer's charge-off recommendation
,"9210.5:Closing, reporting and remittance requirements for charge-offs"
,9211.1:Hardest Hit Fund
,9212.1:Mortgage assistance funds
,9301.1:Foreclosures on Freddie Mac Mortgages
,9301.2:General Servicer requirements for Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters
,9301.3:Freddie Mac's rights
,9301.4:Pre-foreclosure referral account review
,9301.5:Referral to foreclosure
,9301.6:When to refer a Mortgage to foreclosure – Primary Residence
,9301.7:When to refer a Mortgage to foreclosure for a non-Primary Residence
,9301.8:Approving referral to foreclosure on a First Lien Mortgage
,9301.9:Referral to foreclosure documentation requirements
,9301.10:Choosing a judicial or nonjudicial foreclosure process
,9301.11:Obtaining the original Note
,9301.12:Foreclosing in the Servicer's name
,9301.13:Solicitation during the foreclosure process
,9301.14:Servicer's responsibility to work with foreclosure counsel
,9301.15:Reporting requirements
,9301.16:What is the first legal action in the foreclosure process?
,9301.17:Expedited foreclosure if property is vacant or abandoned
,9301.18:Obtaining judgment for less than total indebtedness
,9301.19:Expedited foreclosures
,9301.20:Expedited foreclosures – Florida
,9301.21:Expedited foreclosures – Illinois
,9301.22:Expedited foreclosures – New York
,9301.23:When to preserve/waive deficiency rights
,9301.24:Circumstances where preserving deficiency rights requires additional expense
,9301.25:Abandonment
,9301.26:Preserving the property during the foreclosure process
,9301.27:Expenses that may become First Liens on the property
,9301.28:Complete Borrower Response Packages received after referral to foreclosure
,9301.29:Reviews and certifications prior to foreclosure sale
,9301.30:Foreclosure sale date extensions
,9301.31:Delegated bidding
,9301.32:When to obtain a credit bid for foreclosure sale bidding
,9301.33:Requirements for and reimbursement of appraisal reports
,9301.34:Bidding instructions for First Lien Mortgages not covered by mortgage insurance or subject to credit enhancements
,9301.35:Bidding instructions for Mortgages covered by mortgage insurance or subject to credit enhancements
,9301.36:Bidding instructions for Mortgages insured by the FHA or guaranteed by the VA or RHS
,9301.37:Bidding appropriately and pursuit of surplus proceeds or overbid funds
,9301.38:Reporting foreclosure sale results
,9301.39:Rollbacks
,9301.40:Delivery of clear and marketable title
,9301.41:Vesting the title and avoiding transfer taxes
,9301.42:Reporting and remittance requirements for redemptions and confirmation date changes
,"9301.43:Third-party sale proceeds, reimbursement of expenses and reporting and remittance requirements"
,9301.44:File retention for foreclosure proceedings
,9301.45:State foreclosure timelines
,9301.46:Allowable delays in completing a foreclosure
,9301.47:State foreclosure timeline performance assessment
,9401.1:Bankruptcy
,9401.2:Freddie Mac's rights
,9401.3:Bankruptcy general requirements
,9401.4:Multiple bankruptcy filings
,9401.5:Notifying Freddie Mac of bankruptcy proceedings
,9401.6:Managing new bankruptcy filings
,9401.7:Managing Mortgages that become delinquent subsequent to bankruptcy filing
,9401.8:Bankruptcy cramdowns
,9401.9:Servicing bankruptcies on Mortgages secured by income properties
,"9401.10:Selecting bankruptcy counsel, bankruptcy referrals and the Servicer's responsibility to work with bankruptcy counsel"
,9401.11:Reimbursement of expenses related to a bankruptcy
,9402.1:Freddie Mac rights
,9402.2:Routine and non-routine litigation
,9402.3:Reporting and notification requirements for litigation
,9402.4:Counsel retained by Servicers pursuant to Servicer's duty to indemnify Freddie Mac
,9501.1:Servicer's management of law firms for Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters
,9501.2:Review and evaluation of firms
,9501.3:Firm Minimum Requirements
,9501.4:Selection of firm
,9501.5:Retention of firm
,9501.6:Training of firms
,9501.7:Referral of Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters to firm
,9501.8:Prohibitions related to Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters
,9501.9:Servicer use of connectivity and invoice processing system
,9501.10:Servicer reporting on Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters
,9501.11:Servicer monitoring and management of firm
,9501.12:Escalation of firm issues to Freddie Mac
,"9501.13:File transfers, termination and suspension of firms"
,9501.14:Implementing file transfers and/or the termination and suspension of firms
,9501.15:Reservation of rights and remedies for non-compliance concerning litigation
,"9502.1:Retention of counsel for Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters referred prior to August 1, 2013"
,"9502.2:Litigation counsel eligibility criteria for Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters referred prior to August 1, 2013"
,"9502.3:How to select foreclosure counsel for Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters referred prior to August 1, 2013"
,"9502.4:Selecting bankruptcy counsel for Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters referred prior to August 1, 2013"
,"9502.5:Foreclosure time line compensatory fee protection for use of designated counsel when required for Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters referred prior to August 1, 2013"
,"9502.6:Prohibitions relating to foreclosure and bankruptcy referrals for Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters referred prior to August 1, 2013 and Freddie Mac remedies for non-compliance"
,"9502.7:Providing information to the foreclosure counsel and Servicer use of connectivity and invoice processing systems for Freddie Mac Default Legal Matters referred prior to August 1, 2013"
,9601.1:Working with vendors to collect deficiencies
,9601.2:Assigning deficiency rights after the foreclosure sale
,9601.3:Charging off the deficiency
,9602.1:Servicer reporting of foreclosure sales to credit repositories
,9602.2:Servicer reporting to the IRS
,9603.1:General Servicer requirements for REO properties
,9603.2:FHA/VA/RHS claim filing
,9603.3:Primary mortgage insurance claim filing
,9603.4:Offers to purchase the property with a pending mortgage insurance claim
,9603.5:Receipt of claim payment
,"9603.6:Reduced, suspended or denied claims"
,9603.7:Remittance of primary mortgage insurance claim payments
,9603.8:Property Condition Certificate (PCC) process
,9603.9:Required REO documentation and reporting
,9603.10:Notifying the taxing authority/HOA of REO
,9603.11:Property insurance for REO
,9603.12:Canceling utilities for REO
,"9603.13:Condominium/HOA or Cooperative Corporation assessments, ground rents and property taxes for REO"
,9603.14:Eviction requirements for REO
,9603.15:Reimbursement of expenses incurred on an REO property
,9603.16:Final settlement between the Servicer and Freddie Mac for REO
,9603.17:Late execution of REO repurchase
,9701.1:Reimbursement of expenses
,9701.2:Servicer expense approval authority
,9701.3:Request for pre-approval (RPA)
,9701.4:Freddie Mac's rights concerning expense reimbursement
,9701.5:Expense reimbursement submission time frames
,9701.6:Reimbursement of property taxes
,9701.7:Reimbursement of insurance premiums
,9701.8:Reimbursement of liens
,9701.9:Reimbursement for property inspection and property preservation expenses
,"9701.10:Reimbursement of condominium/HOA or Cooperative Corporation assessments, and ground rents"
,9701.11:Reimbursement of fees and costs incurred during legal proceedings
,9701.12:Reimbursement requirements when foreclosure must be restarted
,9701.13:Reimbursement of BPO/appraisal reports
,9701.14:Reimbursement of Scheduled Principal
,9701.15:Non-reimbursable expenses
,9701.16:Denials and adjustments of expense reimbursement requests
,9701.17:Default reporting requirements and reimbursement of claims
,9701.18:REO related costs and expenses
,9701.19:Expense offsets
,9701.20:Forwarding remittances to Freddie Mac
,9701.21:Standard supporting documentation for expense reimbursement
,9701.22:Expense reimbursement audits
,9701.23:Consent Agreement terms and conditions
tel:800-373-3343,+1-800-FREDDIE
/app/guide/,
/app/guide/segment/Seller%2FServicer%20Relationship,Seller/Servicer Relationship
/app/guide/segment/Selling,Selling
/app/guide/segment/Servicing,Servicing
/app/guide/bulletins,Bulletins & Industry Letters
/app/guide/glossary,Glossary
/app/guide/forms,Forms
https://sf.freddiemac.com/tools-learning/uniform-instruments/2021-updated-instruments,Uniform Instruments(opens in new window)
https://sf.freddiemac.com/working-with-us/selling-delivery/overview,Selling & Delivery(opens in new window)
https://sf.freddiemac.com/working-with-us/origination-underwriting/overview,Origination & Underwriting(opens in new window)
https://sf.freddiemac.com/working-with-us/servicing/overview,Servicing(opens in new window)
https://sf.freddiemac.com/tools-learning/freddie-mac-learning/overview,Freddie Mac Learning(opens in new window)
http://www.freddiemac.com/capital-markets/,Freddie Mac Capital Markets(opens in new window)
http://freddiemac.com,FreddieMac.com(opens in new window)
https://sf.freddiemac.com/,Freddie Mac Single-Family(opens in new window)
https://mf.freddiemac.com/,Freddie Mac Multifamily(opens in new window)
http://www.freddiemac.com/terms/,Terms of Use(opens in new window)
https://www.freddiemac.com/terms/privacy,Privacy(opens in new window)
https://www.freddiemac.com/terms/state_privacy_notices,State Privacy Notices(opens in new window)
https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/freddiemacsf/,(opens in new window)
https://twitter.com/FreddieMacSF,(opens in new window)